Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Motion Pictures Documenting Baseball
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, motion pictures documenting baseball
1945-1998
RU 970
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
33.25
(24 motion pictures)
The materials consist of 16mm films produced by Ethan Allen Films on Sports [?] around 1960 in cooperation with the Yale University Athletic Association. The films, made for distribution to amatuer and professional teams, demonstrate baseball technique using Yale baseball players. Ethan Allen, Yale baseball coach from 1946 to 1968, narrates the films. Also included are videotapes of games and other team events.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
Allen, Ethan, 1904-1993
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Department of Athletics, Yale University, 2004-2005.
Conditions Governing Access
Original motion picture films, as well as preservation masters and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers needing to consult the original materials should refer to the finding aid for policies governing reproduction for access.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of 16mm films produced by Ethan Allen Films on Sports [?] around 1960 in cooperation with the Yale University Athletic Association. The films, made for distribution to amatuer and professional teams, demonstrate baseball technique using Yale baseball players. Ethan Allen, Yale baseball coach from 1946 to 1968, narrates the films. Also included are videotapes of games and other team events.
Baseball; College athletes; College sports; Motion pictures (visual works); Videotapes; Yale University -- Baseball; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Men's baseball films, circa 1960; Accession 2005-A-124
  Scope and Contents
  The accession consists of 16mm films produced by Ethan Allen Films on Sports [?] around 1960 in cooperation with the Yale University Athletic Association. The films, made for distribution to amatuer and professional teams, demonstrate baseball technique using Yale baseball players. Ethan Allen, Yale baseball coach from 1946 to 1968, narrates the films.
  - Training and Conditioning, circa 1960; film reel (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Bats, circa 1960; 2 (Box 2–3)
  - Bird Dog, circa 1960; film reel (16mm) (Box 4)
  - First & Third Base, circa 1960; 3 (Box 5–7)
  - Catching, circa 1960; 2 (Box 8–9)
  - Pitching, circa 1960; 3 (Box 10–12)
  - Shortstop & Second Base, circa 1960; 3 (Box 13–15)
  - Outfielding, 1960; film reel (16mm) (Box 16)
  - Base Running, 1960; film reel (16mm) (Box 17)
  - Batting & Bunting, 1960; film reel (16mm) (Box 18)
- Men's baseball videorecordings, 1945-1998; Accession 2006-A-067
  - 1895 Team 50th Reunion, 1945; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - Baseball Fundamentals (narrated by Ethan Allen), Circa 1960s; videotape (VHS) (Box 2–3)
  - NCAA Honors Luncheon with George Bush, 1986; videotape (VHS) (Box 4)
  - AA All-Star Game (Yale Field), 1998 July 8; videotape (VHS) (Box 5)
  - Yale Baseball Team in Korea, undated; videotape (VHS) (Box 6)